(
"ai_sub_version": "1.10.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
もっと！
More!
にこにこ！
Smile smile!
あらあら。
Oh my, oh my.
は…ん？
Hm...?
眠たい…
I'm sleepy...
ちょこも眠たい。
Choco is sleepy too.
ちょこ…
Choco...
待て待て待て待て！
Wait wait wait wait!
ごっち？
This way?
やだやだやだやだ！
No no no no!
どうも、ホロライブ二期生、悪魔の保健医、癒月ちょこです。
Hello, Hololive 2nd Gen, Devilish School Nurse, Yuzuki Choco here.
お前何人じゃ！
Who are you?!
うわあああ！
Waaaaah!
Thank you Super Chat, thank you very much.
おら、豚、登って。頑張って、豚。
Hey, pig, climb. Do your best, pig.
おら、豚。ごっちよごっち。
Hey, pig. It's this way, this way.
どっち？
Which way?
はいはいはいはい。
Yes yes yes yes.
なんだろう。
I wonder what it is.
何年やってると思ってるんですか？
How many years do you think I've been doing this?
先生に向かってなんですかその言葉遣いは？
What is that language towards your teacher?
友達じゃないんですよ。
We are not friends.
いいですか？癒月ちょこ先生だからね。
Okay? It's Yuzuki Choco Sensei.
お、やばい！うわああ！
Oh, crap! Waaaaah!
美味しかったの…
It was delicious...
あ、違う！だめ！ああああ！
Ah, no! Stop! Aaaaaah!
ちょこしかおらん。
There's only Choco left.
なんか動いた！なんだあいつ！
Something moved! What is that guy?!
はい、いらっしゃいませ。
Yes, welcome.
どこ見てんのよ？見てたでしょ…なあああ！
Where are you looking? You were looking... Hey!
おやすみ…
Good night...
うっす。
Sup.
あー、いい天気。
Ah, nice weather.
保健室のベッドでお昼寝したい。
I want to nap in the infirmary bed.
ズル休み、許されない…
Skipping class isn't allowed...
保健室は神聖なの。
The infirmary is sacred.
サボってる？ちょっとだけ。
Slacking off? Just a little.
誰も来なきゃやる気でない。
If no one comes, I have no motivation.
ちょこちょこせんせーしょん Yeah!
Choco Choco Sensation Yeah!
ちょこちょこせんせーしょん。
Choco Choco Sensation.
このままじゃ私ダメみたい。
At this rate, I might be no good.
ああ、起きなきゃ、当番だから…
Ah, gotta wake up, it's my duty...
二回目のあくび、おやすみなさい。
Second yawn, goodnight.
ごめんなさい。
I'm sorry.
少しだけ寝かせて、先生モード…
Let me sleep a bit more, Sensei Mode...
…シャットダウン。
...Shut Down.
夢見るふわふわ。
Dreaming fluffy.
ずっとこうして眠りたい。
I want to sleep like this forever.
ありがとう、ぽかぽか。
Thank you, warm and fuzzy.
今日は退屈消してるだけ。
Today I'm just killing boredom.
急展開、刺激的ね。
Sudden turn of events, how stimulating.
急に君が来るなんて。
To think you'd come so suddenly.
ねえ、どこか悪いの？
Hey, is something wrong?
何かを期待しているのかな？
Are you expecting something?
揺らう心、巡る感情。
Swaying heart, circulating emotions.
口溶け甘いせんせーしょん。
Melt-in-mouth sweet sensation.
癒されたい、甘えていたい。
Want to be healed, want to be spoiled.
構ってよ ちょこせんせーしょん。
Pay attention to me, Choco Sensation.
君の視線、君の体温。
Your gaze, your body temperature.
わかっても恋は測れない。
Even if I know, love cannot be measured.
元気なのに溜息しちゃう。
Sighing even though I'm healthy.
もしかして何かの病？
Could it be some kind of sickness?
でもドキドキするまで動けないから。
But I can't move until my heart pounds.
ときめき運んで来て My students.
Bring me the excitement, my students.
ズル休み、また来たの？
Skipping class, you came again?
保健室は神聖なの。
The infirmary is sacred.
サボってる？今日だけ。
Slacking off? Just for today.
やっぱり君にいて欲しい。
I want you to be here after all.
明日は週末、お休み。
Tomorrow is the weekend, day off.
なんだよ？家飲み？
What is it? Drinking at home?
最高！
Awesome!
引きこもり？最高！
Shut-in? Awesome!
もちろん、ノーメイク。
Of course, no makeup.
チャイムが鳴ったら白衣着ます。
When the chime rings, I'll put on my white coat.
さあ全てを見せて。
Come on, show me everything.
ちゃんと診断できないじゃん。
I can't diagnose you properly.
何を隠してるの？
What are you hiding?
鼓動のスピードは聞こえてるよ。
I can hear the speed of your heartbeat.
見せて心、めくるシャツ。
Show me your heart, lifting up your shirt.
正常保てる？現状そう。
Can you maintain normality? Seems like it now.
愛されたい、頼られたい。
Want to be loved, want to be relied on.
構ってよ ちょこせんせーしょん。
Pay attention to me, Choco Sensation.
君の重み、君の匂い。
Your weight, your scent.
わかっても愛は測れない。
Even if I know, love cannot be measured.
大好きだから溜息しちゃう。
I sigh because I love you.
やっぱりそれは恋の病。
As I thought, that is lovesickness.
でもドキドキするまで動けないから。
But I can't move until my heart pounds.
ときめき運んで来て My students.
Bring me the excitement, my students.
間違いだって。
Even if it's a mistake.
この世界だって。
Even in this world.
みんな癒しが必要だから。
Because everyone needs healing.
ちょこちょこせんせーしょん Yeah!
Choco Choco Sensation Yeah!
絶対君もダメにしたい。
I definitely want to spoil you too.
揺らぐ心 巡る感情
Wavering heart, swirling emotions...
不治の病？
Is it an incurable disease?
先生 処方箋
Doctor, a prescription!
癒されたい 甘えていたい
I want to be healed, I want to be spoiled.
頼ってよ ちょこ先生ーション
Rely on me, Choco Sensation!
君の視線 君の体温
Your gaze, your body temperature...
わかっても
Even if I understand them...
恋は測れない
Love cannot be measured.
元気なのに
Even though I'm fine,
ダメージしちゃう
I take damage.
もしかしても 手遅れ
Could it be too late?
でもドキドキするまで動けないから
But I can't move until my heart pounds...
ときめき運んで インジェクションです
Carrying excitement, it's an injection!
ちょこちょこ 先生ーション Yeah!
Choco Choco Sensation Yeah!
絶対 君も
I definitely want to...
ダメにしたい
...ruin you too.
はーい！ということで
Okay! So, with that...
癒月ちょこ生誕祭2026
Yuzuki Choco Birthday Festival 2026...
始まりましたー！
...has begun!
見て見て
Look, look!
一曲目からちょこ
Right from the first song, Choco...
生まれ変わりました！
...has been reborn!
いや今日はね 原点回帰ということで
Well, today is about 'returning to the roots'...
ちょこの なんと
so Choco's... surprisingly...
保健室ステージなの！
...it's a School Infirmary stage!
いや ちょっと 保健室もちょっと生まれ変わって
Yeah, the infirmary has also been reborn a bit...
めちゃめちゃ可愛くなりました！
...and became super cute!
シチュエーションドラマとかできそうだよね
Looks like we could do a situation drama here, right?
今日は生まれ変わったニューちょこと
Today, with the reborn New Choco...
素敵なね ゲスト様を
...and wonderful guests...
いっぱい呼んで ライブをしていくんだけど
...I invited many of them for a live performance, but...
その前に
Before that...
みんな ちょこのこと もっと見たいよね？
Everyone, you want to see more of Choco, right?
あーでも まだダメだよ？
Ah, but... not yet, okay?
これから来る お二人に
To the two coming up next...
ちょこの撮影会を ご依頼しちゃいました！
...I requested a photoshoot of Choco!
それでは早速呼んでいきましょう
So, let's call them out right away.
ノエル様ー！
Noel-sama!
ラミィ様ー！
Lamy-sama!
せーの！
One, two!
ちょこ先生
Choco-sensei...
お誕生日
...Happy...
おめでとう！
...Birthday!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
ということで今回はね
So, this time...
この可愛い両手に花で
...with these cute 'flowers in both hands'...
可愛いお二人に
...with these two cuties...
ちょっとね ちょこの撮影会を
...I'm going to have them do a Choco photoshoot.
してってもらおうと思うんですけど
まずは自己紹介よろしくお願いします
First, please introduce yourselves.
ノエルちゃんから
Starting with Noel-chan.
はい！こんまっする～
Yes! Kon-muscle!
ホロライブ三期生の白銀ノエルと...
I'm Hololive 3rd Gen, Shirogane Noel, and...
はーい！ホロライブ五期生の
Haaai! I'm Hololive 5th Gen...
顔が肝臓 雪花ラミィです
...the face is the liver, Yukihana Lamy!
今日はよろしくお願いします
Please treat us well today!
まあね ちょっとちょこ先生の 本当に可愛くなったところ
Well, since Choco-sensei has become truly cute...
ちょっと団長頑張って 攻めていこうと思いますので
...Dancho will do her best to attack aggressively.
よろしくお願いします
Thank you!
攻めちゃって 攻めちゃって！
Attack me, attack me!
ラミィも攻めるよね？
Lamy will attack too, right?
ラミィもギリギリを攻めていきたいと思います
Lamy will also push it to the limit!
いや撮影会やるなら
Well, if we're doing a photoshoot...
ちょっとね このお二人を呼ぶしかないかなと思って
...I thought I had no choice but to call these two.
呼んじゃいました！
So I called them!
いや しかもしかも
Also, also!
ちょっと後で
A little later...
この3人から
...from the three of us...
なんとお知らせもあるみたいなので
...it seems there is also a surprise announcement!
気になる 気になる！
I'm curious, I'm curious!
まぁ 撮影会のあとで
Well, after the photoshoot...
皆さま楽しみにしといてください
...everyone, please look forward to it!
それじゃちょっと こちらで撮影会
Alright then, let's start the photoshoot over here.
よろしくお願いします
Let's do this.
いくよー！
Let's go!
なんかすごいとこ来たぞ
We've come to an amazing place.
すごい！
Amazing!
可愛いでしょう 可愛いでしょう
It's cute, isn't it? Isn't it cute?
撮影会はちょこの ここの診察室でやります
We'll do the photoshoot here in Choco's examination room.
ちょこセンの診察室～！
Choco-sensei's examination room!
でもさ診察室だけどベットは？
But since it's an examination room, where's the bed?
ベットどこ？
Where's the bed?
なんかパネルもあるけどあれ使う？
There's a panel too, are we using that?
あ ちょっとそこは！後でメン限で使うの！
Ah, wait! I'm using that later for Members-only!
あ、え、ダメなの？
Oh, eh, we can't?
そこは後のメン限で使うの！
I'm using that later for Members-only!
なに？！
What?!
メン限で？！
For Members-only?!
そう！ちょっとね、ベットとか...
Yes! Just, you know, with the bed...
ちょっと色々撮影会とかシチュエーションドラマとかやろうかなと！
I was thinking of doing a photoshoot and some situation dramas!
シチュエーションドラマ？！
Situation dramas?!
とんでもないことをしようとしてる！
She's trying to do something outrageous!
ホントだよ！
Seriously!
えへへへ！
Ehehehe!
いや、そうなんですよー。
No, well, that's right.
まあね、ま、それは置いといて！
But anyway, let's put that aside!
あ、置いとくんだ。
Ah, putting it aside.
ちょっと今回は二人に撮影をしてもらいたいので、まずは...
This time I want you two to take photos, so first...
わかりました！
Understood!
撮りますよ！
I'll take them!
ラミィ様には...
For Lamy-sama...
カメラ！
A camera!
え、本格的な！
Eh, it's professional!
すごい！カメラ来た！
Wow! A camera!
そしてノエル様にはこちらの... ジャジャン！
And for Noel-sama, this... Ta-da!
なんだいこれ？
What's this?
ちょこのギリギリを守るために特別に作られたモザイク棒です！
A mosaic stick made specially to protect Choco's borderline areas!
特別仕様きたー！
A special edition arrived!
モザイク？！なんとこれで...
Mosaic?! And with this...
ボタンでこのモザイクの粗さを変えれるらしい！
It seems you can change the roughness of the mosaic with a button!
今めっちゃ粗くなってるから。
It's really rough right now.
あ、ホントだ薄くできる！
Ah, really! You can make it lighter!
すげえ！
Amazing!
でもなんか粗いほうがむしろいいまであるなこれ。
But the rougher one might actually be even better.
確かに！
True!
隠すや！
Hide it!
これ大丈夫かな？
Is this okay?
でも配信、ね、ちょっと守りますよ！
But I'll protect the stream, okay!
ちょこの配信を守ってください！
Please protect Choco's stream!
頑張ります！
I'll do my best!
それでは撮影会スタート！
Now then, photoshoot start!
イェーイ！
Yay!
まずはやっぱ全身？
First is full body, right?
そうだね。
That's right.
普通にこうね、ちょっとポーズ...いつものちょこ戦の！
Normally like this, a pose... The usual Choco-sensei!
おおー！
Ooh!
こんな感じ？
Like this?
ああー！
Aah!
美しい！
Beautiful!
ああ、いいねいいね！
Ah, nice, nice!
かわいい！
Cute!
もうここちょっとマズイんじゃないのここ！
Wait, isn't this part a bit dangerous?!
マズイかな？
Is it dangerous?
なんか逆に？！
Isn't it worse?!
逆に？！
Worse?!
ノリノリなんですけど！
She's really getting into it!
マズイかな？
Is it dangerous?
ちょっと、ちょっとね！
Wait, just a bit!
ちょっとここ揺れて...
It's shaking here...
モザイクが追いついてない！
The mosaic isn't catching up!
追いついて...
Catching up...
じゃノエル様頑張って頑張って！
Noel-sama, do your best!
頑張ります！
I'll do my best!
こうやってね... こういう感じでね！
Like this... just like this!
ちょっとジャンプしてもらってみてもらっても...
Can you try jumping a little for us...
あ、ジャンプ確かに！
Ah, jumping, true!
えい！
Ei!
あ、ダメダメダメ！めっちゃ揺れてる！
Ah, no no no! It's shaking so much!
あかんてしょこれ！
That's no good!
おいおいおい！
Oi oi oi!
あら！
Oh my!
え、ちょっとせっかくだから椅子とか座っちゃう？
Eh, since we're here, wanna sit on the chair?
あ、椅子？
Ah, chair?
椅子ね、ここに。
Chair, it's right here.
ありますね。
Here it is.
はーい。
Okaaay.
椅子！よいしょ。
Chair! Up we go.
おお、いいね！
Ooh, nice!
靴も可愛い！
The shoes are cute too!
なんかちょっと青っぽいんだね！
They're a bit blueish!
あ、そう、ちょこね...
Ah, yes, Choco's...
底が赤なの！
The soles are red!
あ、えー？！
Ah, eeeh?!
ま、まずい！まずい！
B-bad! Bad!
ああ、ありがとうございます！
Aah, thank you very much!
底がね、赤なのこれが！
The soles, you see, they're red!
すごいね！
Amazing!
大丈夫？
Is it okay?
あ、でもなんか見えてないからね。
Ah, but nothing's visible, so.
大丈夫です！
It's fine!
セーフです！
It's safe!
守ってます！
Protecting it!
チャンネル守ってます！
Protecting the channel!
え、じゃあこうどんどん、どんどん上を...見てもらって！
Eh, then keep looking more and more... upwards!
あ、いいね！
Ah, nice!
あら可愛い！
Oh, cute!
見えてる？
Can you see?
見えてるよ！見えてるよ！
We can see! We can see!
見えてる！
We see it!
ああ可愛い！
Ah, cute!
可愛いね！
It's cute!
いー！
Yaaay!
え、ちなみにラミィさん...
Eh, by the way Lamy-san...
はい！
Yes!
あれですよ、この...
It's that thing, this...
椅子に座って先生ポーズも撮って欲しい！
I want you to take the Sensei pose while sitting on the chair!
先生ポーズってなんだ？
What's the Sensei pose?
こんな感じ？
Like this?
ああー！いいですね！いい！
Aah! That's good! Good!
モザイクいらないね、これは！
We don't need mosaic for this one!
非常にいい！
Very good!
本当に要らないのかなこれ。
Do we really not need it?
いや分かんない、分かんない。
No, I don't know, I don't know.
ちょこ戦の魅力が溢れすぎてて！
Choco-sensei's charm is overflowing too much!
いいですね！
It's nice!
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
え、じゃあ団長もいいですか？
Eh, can Danchou ask too?
なに、なに、なに？
What, what, what?
お尻フリフリ、ちょっとしていただきたいんで。
I'd like you to shake your butt a little.
ちょっとフリフリ...
Shake it a little...
えーと、そう後ろ向いてもらって...
Umm, yes, turn around...
白衣越しだけど...
It's through the lab coat, but...
フリフリ！
Shake shake!
あ、いいね！
Ah, nice!
白衣越しだが！
It's through the lab coat, but!
その下に！
Underneath that!
あ、ちょっとその下に！
Ah, wait, underneath that!
スカート結構際どい！
The skirt is pretty risky!
白衣ってこれ脱いで欲しいんだけど、これ脱げないの？
I want you to take off the lab coat, can't you take it off?
ぬ、脱げるけどメン限でって言ってた。
I-I can take it off but I said 'in Members-only'.
あ、メン限なら脱いでくれるんですね！
Ah, so you'll take it off in Members-only!
え、ガニ股、あのココ会長リスペクトで！
Eh, Ganimata... Out of respect for Coco Kaichou!
団長ガニ股好きなんで！
Danchou loves the Ganimata pose!
うわあー！
Uwaaaah!
はい！
Yes!
ガニ股！
Ganimata!
あ、いいね！
Ah, nice!
ガニ股助かる！
Ganimata, thanks for the treat!
ガニ股ー！
Ganimataaa!
これちょっとモザイク！モザイク！
This needs mosaic! Mosaic!
ちょ、見えてるもん！な！
Wait, it's visible! Hey!
モザイクお願いします！
Mosaic please!
モザイクがむしろここが...
The mosaic is actually here...
ちょ、やばい！
Wait, dangerous!
逆にヤバイ！
Conversely dangerous!
ヤバイ、ヤバイ、ヤバイ、ヤバイ！
Bad, bad, bad, bad!
バイバーイ！
Bye-byeee!
可愛い！
Cute!
うーん！
Hnn!
どんどん行こう！
Let's keep going!
じゃあ、ラストはやっぱアイドルだからさ。
Then, since you're an idol, for the last one.
ちょこ戦アイドル！
Choco-sensei idol!
とびっきりのかわいいアイドルお願いします！
A super cute idol pose please!
はーい！
Okaaay!
えー！可愛い！
Eeeh! Cute!
あ、いい猫！
Ah, nice cat!
アップいい！顔のアップいいえ！
Good close-up! The face close-up is nice!
たまらんです。
Irresistible.
かーわーいーい！
So cuuuute!
うーん！
Mmm!
オッケー！
Okay!
あ、いっぱいいただいた！
Ah, I got plenty of shots!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
いや、ちょっとね、この続きはちょっとメン限でやらせていただきますので。
Well, we'll continue this in the membership-only stream.
はい！
Yes!
メン限ではちょっと、歌も、撮影会も...
In the membership stream, we'll have songs, a photoshoot...
うん！
Yeah!
シチュエーションドラマも、なんと２本やっちゃいます！
And surprisingly, we'll do two situation dramas!
おぉー！
Ooh!
楽しみだー！
Can't wait!
ちなみにさ...
By the way...
なんかタイトルとかあるの？そのシチュエーションドラマって。
Do those situation dramas have titles?
あ、今回のタイトルが...
Ah, the titles this time are...
うんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
「先生と...」
"With Sensei..."
「ベッドで...」
"...in bed..."
「特別バレンタイン」
"...a Special Valentine."
あぁ〜！特別！
Aaaah! Special!
たまらん、たまらん！
I can't take it! I can't!
先生とベッドで特別バレンタイン？！
A special Valentine with Sensei in bed?!
おぉーい！
Ooooi!
ってタイトルと...
That title, and...
あと...
Also...
「診察室で...」
"...in the examination room..."
「甘い処方箋を」っていう...
"...a sweet prescription."
えぇー！ママぁー！
Eeeeh! Mamaaa!
ママぁー！
Mamaaa!
ママ、ママ！
Mama, mama!
あの...
Um...
最高すぎる。
That's too awesome.
目線も、ちょっとカメラマンさんをベッドに横たわらせて...
For the angle, I had the cameraman lie down on the bed...
えっ？！
Eh?!
ちょっとみんなが本当に...
So that everyone can really...
本当に見えるように、ちょこが覆いかぶさるように...
...really see it as if Choco is leaning over them...
すごい！
Wow!
たまらーん！
I can't take iiit!
ちょっと、あれ、いろんな画角で撮って行きたいと思います。
I'm planning to shoot from various angles.
え、楽しみ！
Eh, I can't wait!
楽しみだー！
So excited!
お楽しみにー！
Look forward to it!
ということでそろそろお時間が...
Anyway, it's about time...
迫ってきたので...
...we're running out of time...
ちょっとライブの方に戻りたいと思います！
So I think we should head back to the live!
こんな気持ちでね、ちょっとライブだった！
With this mood? Wait, it's a live!
そうだった！
That's right!
急げー！
Hurry!
急げ、急げー！
Hurry, hurry!
うわぁー！
Waaah!
やばい、やばい、やばい！
Oh no, oh no, oh no!
はーい、というわけで！
Okay, so!
このあと...
After this...
二人それぞれ、ちょっとデュエットしてもらうんだけど...
...I'll have the two of you perform duets separately, but...
ちょっとね、最後に３人でも歌うので...
...we'll also sing as a trio at the very end...
楽しみにしててください！
...so please look forward to it!
楽しみー！
Can't wait!
お楽しみー！
Look forward to it!
お楽しみにー！
Enjoy!
それでは着替えに行きましょうか！
Well then, shall we go get changed?
オッケー！あ、これ？！
Okay! Ah, this?!
すごい！
Amazing!
カーテン！
Curtain!
え、リボンもついてる！
Eh, it even has ribbons!
かわいい！
Cute!
じゃあ、ちょっとカーテンの裏でお着替え！
Alright, let's change behind the curtain!
はーい！
Okaaay!
いってきまーす！
See you soon!
See you!
それでは聴いてください。
Please listen.
サマーチョコレート
Summer Chocolate
ドロドロとメロディ Baby
Melting melody, baby
とろけちゃって Catch me darling
Melting away, catch me darling
Pyu-a Pyu-a ココロふわり
Pyu-a Pyu-a, heart is fluffy
キュルキュル 1, 2
Kyuru kyuru, 1, 2
なんか眠れない夜には
On nights when I just can't sleep
お散歩 特別 Party Time
A walk, a special Party Time
ふたりきり (ヤッター！)
Just the two of us (Yay!)
あの角曲がれば ベンチしかない公園だよ
If we turn that corner, it's a park with nothing but a bench
蒸し暑い空気の中 迷い込むんだ
Wandering into the humid air
コンビニちょっと寄り道 買い出し
Stopping by the convenience store to buy a little something
アイスじゃなくて これがいい
Not ice cream, I want this
甘お酒 ほろよい ウインクで
Sweet alcohol, slightly tipsy, with a wink
ズキューンって ストロング
Shot through the heart, strong
９％じゃもう酔えない
9% isn't enough to get me drunk anymore
ラムで潰して おねがい
Crush me with rum, please
お砂糖はマシマシで 飲みやすく
Extra sugar to make it easy to drink
さとかいらない 灼熱で
I don't need sugar, melt it
さぁ溶かして
In the scorching heat
ごくって飲んで
Gulp it down
くせのある私のことを
Take care of me
大事にしてよ
With all my quirks
ねぇ サマーチョコレート
Hey, Summer Chocolate
ドロドロとメロディ Baby
Melting melody, baby
とろけちゃって Catch me darling
Melting away, catch me darling
Pyu-a Pyu-a ココロふわり
Pyu-a Pyu-a, heart is fluffy
キュルキュル 1, 2
Kyuru kyuru, 1, 2
ちょっと淋しい帰り道
A slightly lonely way home
フラフラ 特別 Bonus Time
Staggering, a special Bonus Time
手をつなごう (Yeah! Yeah!)
Let's hold hands (Yeah! Yeah!)
大きめ Tシャツ 君に借りた
An oversized T-shirt I borrowed from you
ありがとうって
Saying thank you
匂わせみたいにして
Making it look like a hint
困らせたいんだ
I want to trouble you
コンビニまた寄っちゃって
Stopping by the convenience store again
たのしい
This is fun
もう一本だけの 弱い奴
Just one more weak drink
覚悟するべき
You better be prepared
テンパリングが大事
Tempering is important
熱すぎても飽きちゃって
If it's too hot, you'll get bored
冷たいのはだめやだもん
I hate it when it's cold
チョコみたいな私を
Treat me like chocolate
プレシャスにして扱って
Handle me with precious care
微炭酸のお酒で
With lightly carbonated alcohol
シュワシュワシュワ
Fizz, fizz, fizz
愛は伝えなきゃ届かない
Love won't reach you if I don't say it
恋してる証拠に
As proof of my love
ここでチューしてして
Kiss me right here, do it
夜空のグラスに
Into the glass of the night sky
キラキラこぼして
Spilling sparkles
息もできないくらいに
Enough to take my breath away
もうだってだってだって
Geez, but, but, but
恋に溺れて
Drowning in love
君の熱で溶けたら
If I melt with your heat
そのまんまで食べてよ
Eat me just like that
手にベトベトついちゃって
Getting all sticky on your hands
一生一緒
Together forever
官能お酒ほろ酔い
Tipsy on sensual alcohol
ウインクでストロング
Strong with a wink
リキュールじゃもう酔えない
I can't get drunk on liqueur anymore
ラブで潰してお願い
Crush me with love, please
お砂糖はマシマシで
With extra extra sugar
飲みやすさとか要らない
I don't need it to be easy to drink
灼熱でサッと溶かして
Melt me quickly with scorching heat
ゴクって飲んで
Gulp me down
クセのある私だからさ
Because I'm a quirky one
君が選ばれた
You were chosen
サマーチョコレート
Summer Chocolate
ドロドロとろりベイビー
Melty, gooey baby
とろけちゃってキャッチミーダーリン
Melting away, catch me darling
ピュアピュアココアふわり
Pure pure cocoa, fluffy
チュルチュル One Two
Kiss kiss One Two
What's up Japan!
Can you hear me?
It's like getting down.
No money, no job.
Too much bad news.
There is no reason to be down.
It's time to get up.
We have a hot new song.
That's from AKB48.
To make you feel good.
Koisuru Fortune Cookie.
So dance Japan crazy!
あなたのこと
Even though
好きなのに
I like you
私にまるで
You have absolutely
興味ない
no interest in me
何度目かの
Preparing for my
失恋の準備
umpteenth heartbreak
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
周りを見れば
If I look around
大勢の
there are so many
可愛い子たちが
cute girls
いるんだもん
everywhere
地味な花は
You won't notice
気づいてくれない
a plain flower
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
カフェテリア流れる
Music flowing
Music
in the cafeteria
ぼんやり
While listening
聴いていたら
idly
知らぬ間に
Before I knew it,
リズムに合わせ
to the rhythm
つま先から
my toes
動き出す
started moving
止められない今の気持ち
Can't stop this feeling now
Come on Come on Baby
占ってよ
Tell my fortune
恋するフォーチュンクッキー
Falling in Love Fortune Cookie
未来は
The future
そんな悪くないよ
isn't that bad
Hey! Hey! Hey!
ツキを呼ぶには
To call upon luck
笑顔を見せること
you have to show a smile
ハートのフォーチュンクッキー
Heart's Fortune Cookie
運勢
Let's make our luck
今日よりも良くしよう
better than today
Hey! Hey! Hey!
人生捨てたもんじゃないよね
Life isn't something to throw away, right?
あっと驚く奇跡が起きる
A surprising miracle will happen
あなたとどこかで愛し合える予感
A premonition that we'll love each other somewhere
あなたにちゃんと告りたい
I want to confess to you properly.
だけど自分に自信ない
But I have no confidence in myself.
リアクションは想像つくから
Because I can imagine your reaction.
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
性格いい子がいいなんて
"I like girls with good personalities..."
男の子は言うけど
Boys say that, but...
ルックスがアドバンテージ
Looks are an advantage.
いつだって可愛い子が
Cute girls are always...
人気投票1位になる
Number one in the popularity polls.
Please Please Please Oh baby
私も見て
Look at me too.
恋するフォーチュンクッキー
Lovin' Fortune Cookie!
その殻さあ壊してみよう
Come on, let's break that shell.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
先の展開
The future development...
神様も知らない
Even God doesn't know.
涙のフォーチュンクッキー
Tearful Fortune Cookie.
そんなにネガティブにならずに
Don't get so negative!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
世界は愛で溢れているよ
The world is overflowing with love.
悲しい出来事忘れさせる
It makes us forget sad events.
明日は明日の風が吹くと思う
I think tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
Come on, Come on, Come on, Come on baby
占ってよ
Tell my fortune!
恋するフォーチュンクッキー
Lovin' Fortune Cookie!
未来はそんな悪くないよ
The future isn't that bad!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
ツキを呼ぶには
To call upon luck...
笑顔を見せること
Is to show a smile.
ハートのフォーチュンクッキー
Heart's Fortune Cookie.
運勢今日よりもよくしよう
Let's make our luck better than today!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
人生捨てたもんじゃないよね
Life isn't something to throw away, right?
あっと驚く奇跡が起きる
A surprising miracle will happen.
あなたとどこかで愛し合える予感
A premonition that we can love each other somewhere.
君が好きったら君が好き
When I say I like you, I like you!
君が好きったら君が好き！
Pure Pure Pure Pure Love
あのね乙女は本気出すとすごいんです
You know, when a maiden gets serious, she's amazing.
Want you いずれ Shoot you
Want you, eventually shoot you.
あの手この手でライバルを出し抜くの
Outsmarting rivals with every trick in the book.
全部計算済みレシピ通り
Everything's calculated, just like the recipe.
不器用だって武器にして
I'll even make my clumsiness a weapon.
あざといてみたりして
Try acting all cute and cunning.
酔ったフリで甘えて
Pretending to be drunk to act spoiled.
すでに Lock On!
Already locked on!
あー！出遅れた！
Ah! I'm too late!
つまみ食いしたら無くなった
I took a little nibble and now it's gone.
ブランデーや日本酒
Brandy and Sake.
時に Funky
Sometimes funky.
苦いのはNGで
Bitter things are NG.
女の子の季節だもん 全部
It's the season for girls, so everything...
思い通りになってよね
...better go exactly as I planned, okay?
君は私と結ばれます
You will be tied to me.
本命あげちゃう Melting
I'll give you my true love, Melting.
誰にも渡さない大戦争
A great war where I won't hand you over to anyone.
ときめいちゃいます Mercy
It makes my heart throb, Mercy.
それじゃ格好つかないじゃん 内緒のデート
That won't look cool, will it? A secret date.
Sweetie Sweetie Kiss
甘くていいの
Is it okay to be sweet?
Sweetie Sweetie Heart
こういうのがいいっしょ？
This kind of thing is good, right?
カッコいいんだもん
Because it's so cool.
絶対譲らない覚悟です
I'm absolutely resolved not to give up.
本気なのです
I'm serious.
目を見て言って？
Look me in the eye and say it?
君の気持ち
Your feelings.
Pure Pure Pure Pure Love
何度も試作した
I made so many trial versions.
予行練習もした
I even did a rehearsal.
弱気になどなるな
Don't you get weak-hearted now.
大丈夫 自分史上 一番
It's okay, I'm the cutest I've ever been...
かわいい私なんだから
...in my entire history!
君は私と結ばれます
You will be tied together with me.
結ばれる運命なのです
It is our destiny to be together.
本命あげちゃう メルティ
I'll give you my true love, melty.
誰にも渡さない大戦争
A great war where I won't hand you to anyone.
トキメイちゃいます メルシー
My heart is fluttering, merci.
それじゃ手とか繋いじゃう？
Then shall we hold hands?
内緒デート
A secret date.
ズキズキ Kiss
Throbbing Kiss.
甘くていいの
It's okay to be sweet.
ズキズキ Heart
Throbbing Heart.
こういうのがいいっしょ
You like this kind of thing, right?
初恋なんだもん
Because it's my first love.
絶対譲らない覚悟です
I'm prepared to never give you up.
本気なのです
I am serious about this.
目を見て言って
Look me in the eyes and say...
君の気持ち
...how you feel.
Pure love, Pure love...
はい、ということで！チョコ達3人の新曲でした！
Okay! So that was the new song from the three of us Chocos!
イエーイ！
Yay!
いい新曲でしたー
It was a good new song~
改めまして、ノエル様、ラミィ様と...
Once again, together with Noel-sama and Lamy-sama...
...一緒にね、コラボ歌唱した
...we performed a collaboration song...
「初恋大戦争」という新曲なんですけど
...this new track called 'Hatsukoi Daisensou'.
今回、作詞作曲をMedansy様
For this song, lyrics and composition were by Medansy-sama...
そして、編曲をYousuke様にお願いいたしました！
...and we asked Yousuke-sama for the arrangement!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いや、今回のテーマが、バレンタインの日に
So, the theme this time is, on Valentine's Day...
3人の可愛い女の子達が
...three cute girls...
1人の男の子を手に入れるために
...in order to win over one boy...
バチバチにね、出し抜こうとする、みたいな
...are aggressively trying to outwit each other.
激重なテーマ楽曲となっております
It's become a song with quite a heavy theme.
いやもう3人の声が合わさって、めちゃめちゃアイドルソングになっているので
Our three voices combined to make a super idol-like song...
ぜひぜひ皆様、聴いてください！
...so everyone, please definitely listen to it!
聴いてねー
Listen to it~
何回も聴きたいなー
I want to listen to it over and over.
いけるとこまでいこうかなー
I wonder if I can go as far as I can.
いや、こちらの楽曲は、この後24時から
Well, this song will be available after this at 24:00...
2月の15日0時からね、各社音楽サイトにて
...from February 15th at 0:00 on various music sites...
配信されます！
...it will be distributed!
やったー！
Yay!
聴けるー
We can listen to it!
そしてね、この配信後すぐに
And, right after this broadcast...
この楽曲のMVが
...the Music Video for this song...
公開されます！
...will be premiered!
やったー！
Yay!
いやぜひぜひ皆様、いっぱい聴いて、MVの方にも
Everyone, please listen a lot, and for the MV too...
ちょっと感想とかね、コメントいただけたら嬉しいかなって思います
...I'd be happy if you could leave some thoughts or comments.
お願いします！
Please do!
じゃあね、二人とも、今日はありがとう！
Alright then, thank you both for today!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
引き続きね、頑張ってください
Please continue to do your best!
頑張る！ありがとう！
I will! Thank you!
ほならば、おさらばじゃ！
Well then, farewell!
おさらば！ありがとう！
Farewell! Thank you!
そして、ここからライブ後半となります！
And now, the second half of the live begins!
まだまだ、ゲストパートとか
There are still more guest parts...
なんと最後に、重大告知もあるので
...and believe it or not, a huge announcement at the end...
皆様、一緒に楽しんでいきましょう！
...so everyone, let's enjoy it together!
それでは、次のゲストは...こちら！
So then, the next guest is... this person!
急に会いたいって
You said you wanted to see me suddenly.
いつものように準備してる
I'm getting ready just like always.
午前0時過ぎの終電で向かう
Heading there on the last train past midnight.
バカでした
I was a fool.
やめときなよって言われても
Even though I was told to stop...
また会いに行く
...I'm going to see you again.
会いたいから
Because I want to see you.
ぶつかり落ち合う 街の風は少し冷たい
The wind in this city where we bump into each other is a little cold.
慣れないワイン無理やり飲み干してしまってはフラフラ
Forcing myself to down wine I'm not used to, I get all dizzy.
嫌われちゃったらどうしよう
What if you end up hating me?
下手に出ちゃったらどうしよう
What if I act too humble?
少しは残したくない
I don't want to leave even a little bit.
ちょっと期待してね
Keep your expectations up a little, okay?
ずっと見栄張ってね
Keep showing off for me, okay?
周りばかり気にして生きてる
I live my life always worrying about those around me.
ちょっと憂鬱かも
It might be a little depressing.
でもなんか寂しくて Ah
But somehow it feels lonely, ah...
本当は自分じゃイキがって
Actually, I'm just acting tough.
いつも分かったフリして
Always pretending to understand,
そんなんじゃないのに無理して
forcing myself even though I'm not like that.
期待してないフリしても
Even if I pretend I don't expect anything,
やっぱ一番嬉しくて
in the end, I'm the happiest.
取り繕った私は
Is the me who fixed herself up
可愛いかな
cute to you?
今夜は壊れるほど抱きしめて
Tonight, hold me tight enough to break me.
何もかも消えそうな
Everything looks like it might vanish.
糸で繋がってる恋だね
It's a love connected by a single thread.
私が諦めたらきっと
If I were to give up, surely
簡単に消えちゃうね
it would disappear so easily.
引き留めるにはどうする？
What should I do to make you stay?
あの娘だったらどうする？
What would that girl do?
不器用な指
Entwining these
もっと絡めて
clumsy fingers even more.
いつもチェックしてね
Check on me always, okay?
一喜一憂でね
Get happy and sad over every little thing, okay?
他の娘と比べてばかりいた
I was always comparing myself to other girls.
一番見て欲しい Ah
I want you to look at me the most, ah...
目の前のあなたは Ah
The you in front of me, ah...
どこか違う景色見てる
is looking at a scenery somewhere else.
いつも優しいフリして
Always pretending to be kind,
そんなんじゃないのに笑って
laughing even though it's not like that.
近付けば近付くほど
The closer I get to you,
心は遠く感じて
the further my heart feels.
少しずつ離れてく
I can tell
こと分かるよ
we're drifting apart little by little.
今夜は忘れるほど抱きしめて
Tonight, hold me until I forget it all.
自分をもっと強く
If only I could
持てればさよならを
have a stronger sense of self,
言えるのにな
I could say goodbye.
いつも分かったフリして
Always pretending to understand,
そんなんじゃないのに無理して
forcing myself even though I'm not like that.
ふと見せる優しさが
That kindness you show suddenly,
ずっと忘れられなくて
I just can't forget it.
取り繕った私は
Is the me who fixed herself up
可愛いかな
cute to you?
今夜は壊れるほど抱きしめて
Tonight, hold me tight enough to break me.
突然溢れ出した
Suddenly overflowing,
私頑張ったよね
I did my best, didn't I?
いつか振り向いてくれると
Thinking you'd look my way someday,
思っていたのにな
that's what I thought, but...
取り繕った私が
The me who put up a front
剥がれていく
is peeling away.
今夜は忘れるほど抱きしめて
Tonight, hold me until I forget it all.
なんかいつも眠そうだし
You always look kinda sleepy.
なんかいつもつまんなそうだし
You always look kinda bored.
なんかいつもヤバそうだし
You always look kinda sketchy.
なんかいつもスマホいじってるし
You're always playing on your phone.
本当はテンション高いのに
Even though you're actually high energy,
アタシといると低いし
it drops when you're with me.
なんなの自分 ありえなくない？
What is that? Isn't that unbelievable?
嫌い 大嫌い どうでもいい
I hate you, I really hate you, whatever.
だったらボクも言うけどさ
Then I've got something to say too.
ちっちゃいことですぐ怒るし
You get mad at every little thing,
言い返したらすぐ泣くし
and you cry as soon as I talk back.
ごめんって言っても許してくれないし
You don't forgive me even when I apologize.
その割 機嫌が直れば
But as soon as your mood improves,
ケロっとおはようとか言うし
you act like nothing happened and say 'Morning'.
あぁなんて罪深い人なんだ
Ah, what a sinful person you are.
畜生 もう知らないぞ
Dammit, I don't care anymore!
甘い甘い 恋の魔法は
The sweet, sweet magic of love...
散りばめて彩って食べちゃおうか
Shall we sprinkle it, decorate it, and eat it up?
苦い苦い愛の玉手箱
A bitter, bitter treasure box of love.
未来味の不思議なチョコレート
A mysterious chocolate with the taste of the future.
温めて混ぜたらきっと
If we warm it up and mix it together, surely,
いつかお口に合う味になるの
Someday it will become a flavor that suits your taste.
ねえねえ チョコいいんだな？
Hey, hey, chocolate is fine, right?
なんで？
Why?
さっきはあのね ごめんね
About earlier... um, sorry.
なにが？
For what?
いつもモヤってなるじゃん
Things always get kinda hazy, you know?
それで？
And then?
今日はこれを渡したくて
Today, I wanted to give you this.
言葉じゃ足りないからさ
Because words aren't enough.
だから？
So?
受け取ってくれないかな
I was hoping you'd accept it.
なによ？
What is it?
一緒にいてくれてありがとう
Thank you for being with me.
わぁ！なんだよそれ！
Wha-?! What is that!
あなたの優しさについつい甘えちゃう
I unintentionally spoil myself on your kindness.
誰よりも近いから 素直になれない
Since we're closer than anyone, I can't be honest.
君も一生懸命そう ついつい忘れちゃう
You also seem to be trying your hardest, but I just forget.
誰よりも一番 大好きなのに
Even though I love you the most, more than anyone.
甘い甘い夢の宝箱
A sweet, sweet treasure box of dreams.
奇跡味の内緒のチョコレート
A secret chocolate with the taste of miracles.
二人だけのイノベーションを
Searching for an innovation just for the two of us,
探し組み立てたら 賑わおうか
Once assembled, shall we make some noise?
苦い苦い日々の化粧箱
A bitter, bitter cosmetic box of days.
世界味の最初のチョコレート
The very first chocolate with the taste of the world.
冷めきって割れないように
So it doesn't get completely cold and crack,
大事に包んで 生涯の完成まで
Wrap it carefully, until the completion of a lifetime.
いつだって
Always.
病める時も
In sickness,
どんな日も
And in any day.
そう ずっと
Yes, forever.
健やかなる時も
In health as well.
手を取って
Take my hand,
誓い二人を分かつまで
A vow until we are parted.
愛してる
I love you.
僕もそうさ
Me too.
そばにいて
Stay by my side.
そばにいる
I'll be by your side.
なんて嘘かもよ？
Just kidding, maybe?
はぁ そうかい 僕も適当に言った
Hah, really? I just said it randomly too.
甘い甘い
Sweet, sweet...
苦い苦い
Bitter, bitter...
甘い甘い恋の魔法箱
A sweet, sweet magic box of love.
宇宙味の秘密のチョコレート
A secret chocolate with the taste of the universe.
二人だけのデコレーションを
Sprinkling a decoration just for the two of us,
散りばめて彩って食べちゃおうか
Shall we color it and eat it up?
苦い苦い愛の玉手箱
A bitter, bitter treasure box of love.
未来味の不思議なチョコレート
A mysterious chocolate with the taste of the future.
温めて混ぜたら絶対
If we warm it up and mix it, definitely,
いつか最高に幸せな味になるの
Someday it will become the happiest taste ever.
いっせーので！
Ready, set!
Thank you so much!
See you next time!
ねえ 一つだけ聞いていい？
Hey, can I ask you just one thing?
私のこと...
About me...
会えるかも今日は
Perhaps we can meet today,
心が騒いで
My heart is racing.
好きにしたくなった
I wanted to let myself fall in love,
ときめきに踊る瞬間
The moment my heart dances with excitement.
私のことなど
About me,
たぶん気にしてないのだけど
You probably don't care at all, but...
ここにいるんだよ
I am right here!
私はここよ
自信が揺れ動く
My confidence is wavering.
嫌われてないかな
I wonder if you hate me.
勢いでとにかく
With momentum, anyway,
挨拶だ
Let's say hello!
やっと晴れたね ぱっと晴れたね
Finally it's sunny, suddenly it's sunny.
そして元気になるね
And it makes us energetic.
おはようの代わりに
Instead of saying 'Good Morning',
背中を叩いて さあ行くよ
I'll slap your back, come on, let's go!
やっと晴れたら ぱっと晴れたら
If it finally clears up, if it suddenly clears up,
きっと元気な笑顔
Surely you'll have an energetic smile.
なんだか今の
Somehow, just now,
その気持ちが切なくなったよ
That feeling became bittersweet.
授業終わりの空
The sky after class ends,
遠くを眺めた
I gazed into the distance.
恋って甘いもんじゃない
Love isn't just something sweet.
違うかも苦さ半分
Maybe not, it's half bitterness.
さあ、わざと仕込めなくちゃだから
Come on, I gotta play it up on purpose.
動き出そうよ
Let's start moving.
自分らしくね
Just be yourself.
楽しく生きるの
Live life happily.
毎日が奇跡
Every day is a miracle.
言わずに悔やむより
Better than regretting not saying it,
勇気出そう
Let's have courage.
ずっと前から
For a long time,
うんと前から
For a very long time,
聞いてみたくて待ってた
I've been waiting to ask you.
私から最初に
I'll be the first one to,
伝えてしまえ 大好きです
Tell you: "I love you."
ずっと前だよ
It's been a long time,
うんと前だよ
A really long time.
聞いたことに答えて
Please answer what I asked.
どんな風に感じてるの
How do you feel about it?
全部見せてよ
Show me everything.
楽しく生きるの
Live life happily.
毎日が奇跡
Every day is a miracle.
本当は不安でも
Even if I'm actually anxious,
勇気出そう
Let's have courage.
出そう？うん！
Shall we? Yeah!
ずっと前から
For a long time,
うんと前から
For a very long time,
聞いてみたくて待ってた
I've been waiting to ask you.
私から最初に
I'll be the first one to,
伝えてしまえ 大好きです
Tell you: "I love you."
ずっと前だよ
It's been a long time,
うんと前だよ
A really long time.
聞いたことに答えて
Please answer what I asked.
どんな風に感じてるの
How do you feel about it?
全部見せてよ
Show me everything.
世界は恋に落ちている
The world is falling in love.
光の矢 胸を刺す
An arrow of light pierces my chest.
君を分かりたいんだよ
I want to understand you.
ねえ
Hey,
教えて
Tell me.
すれ違う言葉に
In the passing words,
ちょっとだけの後悔
There's a little bit of regret.
涙こぼれた
Tears spilled out.
忙しい感情
My busy emotions,
鼓動にリンクする
Link to my heartbeat.
チューニング
Tuning...
確かめたいんだ
I want to confirm it.
目的ばっかりとらわれて
Obsessed only with the goal,
大事なものが霞んで逃げて
Important things blur and run away.
今日もリスタート
Restarting again today.
世界は恋に落ちている
The world is falling in love.
光の矢 胸を刺す
An arrow of light pierces my chest.
全部分かりたいんだよ
I want to understand everything.
ねえ
Hey,
聞かせて
Let me hear it.
たった1ミリが遠くて
Just one millimeter feels so far.
駆け抜けた日々に
In the days I ran through,
忘れない 忘れられない
I won't forget, I can't forget,
輝く1ページ
This shining page.
お似合いの二人に
For the two who suit each other,
なんだか複雑な
There are some complex...
気持ちがいるよ
Feelings here.
初めての感情
These first-time emotions,
鼓動にリンクする
Link to my heartbeat.
自分のこと わからないまま
Not understanding myself...
あの子にアドバイスまでしちゃって
...I went and gave her advice.
胸が痛いや
My chest hurts.
世界は恋に落ちている
The world is falling in love.
光の矢 胸を刺す
An arrow of light pierces my heart.
気づいたこの想いは もう
I've realized this feeling, but...
遅いの
...it's already too late.
あの子の方がかわいいの
She is cuter than me.
知ってるよ だけど
I know that, but...
「うまくいかないで」なんてね
"I hope it doesn't go well," I say.
逃げ出したくせに
Even though I ran away.
バカ
Idiot.
君のこと全部わかりたいって思っちゃう
I just want to understand everything about you.
これが恋だって初めて気づいたの
I realized for the first time that this is love.
絶対振り向いてほしい
I definitely want you to look my way.
遅かったけど
It was late, but...
諦めたくない
...I don't want to give up.
だって
Because...
好きだから！
...I love you!
春に咲いた花が恋をした
The flower that bloomed in spring fell in love.
花は必死に上を向いて笑った
The flower looked up desperately and smiled.
青い夏の蕾も恋をした
The blue summer bud also fell in love.
咲かない花と火薬の匂い
A flower that won't bloom and the smell of gunpowder.
ホントの気持ち言葉にして
Putting my true feelings into words...
大事なこと話せたら
...if I could speak of what's important...
今日もリスタート
...today is a restart too.
鈍感な君だから
Because you are so dense...
口に出して言わなきゃ
...I have to say it out loud.
今 君に伝えるよ
I'll tell you right now.
ねぇ
Hey...
好きです
I love you.
世界は恋に落ちている
The world is falling in love.
光の矢 胸を刺す
An arrow of light pierces my heart.
全部わかりたいんだよ
I want to understand everything.
「ねぇ 聞かせて」
"Hey, let me hear it."
辿り着いてもう迷わない
I've arrived, I won't hesitate anymore.
駆け抜けた日々に
In the days I ran through...
忘れない忘れられない
...I won't forget, I can't forget...
輝く1ページ
...that one shining page.
はーい ということで
Okay, so...
ここまではアキ様 ロボ子
Up to this point, with Aki-sama, Roboco...
ござるに ふーたん
...Gozaru-ni, and Futan...
と一緒に歌わせていただきました！
...I had the pleasure of singing with them!
みんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone!
さてさて
Now then...
ここからはなんと 重大告知が
...from here, believe it or not, there are important announcements.
二つあります！
There are two of them!
まず一つ目が...
The first one is...
こちら！ドドン！
This! Ta-da!
癒月ちょこ生誕祭2026グッズ！
Yuzuki Choco Birthday Celebration 2026 Goods!
それではちょっと詳しくご紹介していきたいと思います
So, I'd like to introduce them in a bit more detail.
まずはこちら！
First is this!
ちょこのクッション！
Choco's Cushion!
いやこれね いやちょっとちょこの誕生日といえば
Well this... well, speaking of Choco's birthday...
毎年 Nardack先生ありがとうございますということで
...every year, I say thank you to Nardack-sensei...
今年もNardack先生に
...and this year too, Nardack-sensei...
めちゃめちゃ素敵なイラスト
...has drawn a super lovely illustration...
描き下ろしていただきました！
...just for me!
今回のテーマはバレンタインということで
This time's theme is Valentine, so...
ちょっとね ちょこメイトを抱きながら
...while hugging a Chocomate a little...
ちょっと今回はチョコレート風のクッションにしてみました！
...I tried making it a chocolate-style cushion this time!
可愛いでしょ？
Cute, right?
サイズ感がちょうど枕くらいになってるので
The size is just about like a pillow, so...
ちょっとね お昼寝の時とか仮眠用に
...for nap time or for a light sleep...
「スヤァ」ってできる感じで作っちゃいました！
...I made it so you can go "Zzz" comfortably!
そして続いては こちら！
And next is... this!
初めてちょっとね、お菓子が作れる…
For the first time, you can make sweets with...
なんとなんと、ちょこのチョコレート型〜！
Believe it or not, a Choco Chocolate Mold!
耐熱も、冷却も、
It handles heat, it handles freezing,
あったかいのも、冷たいのも、両方使えちゃって！
so you can use it for both hot and cold things!
ちょっとね、しょこらと…
It features Shocola and...
ちょこめいとの今回はチョコレート型になっております。
...the Chocomates, this time in the form of a chocolate mold.
ま、マフィンとかね、
Well, you can make muffins,
クッキーとか、
or cookies,
あとはまあ普通に冷やし固めてチョコレート入れたりとか、
or just simply pour chocolate in and let it harden,
なんか色々使えるから、ぜひ！
you can use it for all sorts of things, so please!
みんなも作ってみてね〜！
Everyone, try making something too!
そして続いてはこちら！お待たせしました！
And next up is this! Thanks for waiting!
ちょこのすやすやぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
Choco's Suyasuya Plush Keychain!
ま、ちょこと言えばね、睡眠ということで、
Well, when you think of Choco, you think of sleep.
超ロングスリーパーのちょこが、
Being the super long-sleeper that I am,
今回はぬいぐるみキーホルダーとなって、
I've become a plush keychain this time,
ちょっとすやすやぬいぐるみで作らせていただきました。
and we made it into a snoozing plushie.
ま、ずっとね、肌身離さず持っていれば、
If you keep it by your side all the time,
いつか「あぁ…」って聞こえてくるかもしれない！
someday you might hear an "Ah..." coming from it!
そして今年もございます。
And we have them this year too.
癒月ちょこ書き下ろし台本の…
Original scripts written by Yuzuki Choco...
耳舐めASMR台本！
Ear-licking ASMR scripts!
撮りましたよ、ちょこのASMRボイス！
I recorded them! Choco's ASMR Voices!
今回ね、耳舐めの方は3つございます。
This time, there are three ear-licking tracks.
一つ目が、『溶けかけのチョコレート』。
The first one is "Melting Chocolate".
いや、こちらはね、あのちょっと…
Well, this one is, um, a little bit...
あの皆様がご想像しているより、
uh, more than you all might be imagining,
ちょっとあの…あの…エチチかもしれないんですけど…
it might be a little... um... um... ecchi...
ま、配信ではね、
Well, it's the kind of voice...
ぜーったいにできないボイスとなっておりますので！
that I can absolutely NEVER do on stream!
ぜひともね、皆様ご購入して、
So please, everyone, purchase it,
聴いてみてください〜！
and give it a listen!
そして、もう一つが、
And another one is...
『残業後のご褒美デザート』ということで！
"Reward Dessert After Overtime"!
こちらはちょことの同棲シチュエーションとなっております。
This one is a living-together situation with Choco.
はい。ちょこが残業をしてきて、帰ってきた時の…
Yes. When Choco comes home after working overtime...
うん、ま、デザートは、
Hmm, well, is the dessert...
ちょこなのか、君なのか、
Choco? Or is it you?
どっちなんだろうね〜？
Which one is it, I wonder?
ま、ちょっと聴いてみてよ！
Well, just give it a listen!
そしてそして！
And, and!
『年下幼馴染のツンデレバレンタイン』ということで、
"Younger Childhood Friend's Tsundere Valentine".
今回はね、聴いている君たちが、
This time, you listeners...
ちょっと隣の家のお兄ちゃんになった気分で聴いてみてください。
...should listen feeling like the older brother next door.
こちらもね、耳舐めボイスとなっておりますが、
This is also an ear-licking voice,
なんとこちら、
but believe it or not,
ドMの方は絶対に聴いていただけたら！
those who are masochists should definitely listen!
ちょっとニコニコしちゃうんじゃないかなって思います。
I think it'll make you grin a little.
はい！そしてそして、フルセットをご購入の方！
Yes! And, and, for those who buy the Full Set!
フルセット特典！
The Full Set Bonus!
今回はなんと初めて！チェキ風ブロマイドカードになりました！
This time, for the first time! It's a Cheki-style Bromide Card!
ちょっとこちらね、数量限定で、
This one, in limited quantities,
直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージが入っております。
will have a handwritten signature & foil-stamped reproduction message.
カキカキしちゃうよ〜！
I'll be scribbling away!
通常バージョンは、箔押し複製サインと複製メッセージが入ります。
The regular version comes with a foil-stamped reproduction signature and message.
そしてね、特典がもう一つ！
And there's one more bonus!
フルセット購入特典として、
As a Full Set Purchase Bonus,
『ヤキモチのぎゅーっ』のASMRボイスが入っております。
the "Jealous Squeeze" ASMR Voice is included.
いや、こちらはね、ちょっとあの…
Well, this one is a bit, um...
甘々の、ぎゅーボイスなので、
it's a super sweet "squeeze" voice,
ま、ちょっとね、普段あんまちょこ嫉妬しないんですけど、
well, Choco usually doesn't get jealous much,
ちょっとま、何に嫉妬してるかは、
but as for what I'm jealous of,
聴いてからのお楽しみなんですけど。
that's a surprise for after you listen.
ちょっとぜひぜひ、ニヤニヤしながら聴いといてください！
Please, by all means, listen to it while grinning!
ぜひ手に入れてください！
Please be sure to get it!
そしてそして！重大告知、二つ目は…
And, and! Major Announcement number two is...
こちらー！
This!
…ねぇ、ちょこたち
...Hey, Chocos.
もう二度と会えないの？
Will we never meet again?
不思議ね、キミの言葉を聞くと
It's strange, when I hear your words,
なんだか元気が出てきちゃう
I somehow feel energized.
辛い感情も、孤独な気持ちも
Painful feelings, lonely feelings,
ちょこが全て食べてあげるわ。
Choco will eat them all for you.
ちょこのことをもっともっと、
I want you to come to love Choco
大好きになってほしい。
more and more.
ねえ、もしよければキミに……
Hey, if it's okay with you...
ちょこの思い出話、聞いてほしいの。
I want you to hear Choco's memories.
12ヶ月連続オリジナル楽曲リリース連動ボイスドラマプロジェクトスタート
12-Month Consecutive Original Song Release & Linked Voice Drama Project Start
はーい！というわけで…
Okaaaay! So that means...
2月15日からオリジナル楽曲12曲連続リリースが決定しましたー！
From February 15th, the release of 12 consecutive original songs has been decided!
しかもこちら、なんとオリ曲に
Moreover, believe it or not, to the original songs...
ストーリー連動のボイスドラマが
...a voice drama linked to the story...
一緒にリリースされます。
...will be released together.
いやこちらね、約1話から12話まで
Well, you see, from episode 1 to 12...
1曲ずつに連動してボイスドラマもあるので
...there is a voice drama linked to each song...
ぜひぜひ楽しみにしててください。
...so please, please look forward to it.
そして今回はね、その記念すべき
And this time, that memorable...
1曲目をこれから披露したいと思います。
...first song, I would like to perform right now.
それでは聴いてください。
Please listen.
キミの秒針。
"Your Second Hand."
まだ戻れないから
Since I can't go back yet...
また愛しさが増す
...my love grows again.
キミに逢いたいよ
I want to see you.
キミから受け取った壊れそうなストーリー
The fragile story I received from you.
どこまでも広がる青い空
The blue sky spreading endlessly.
変わらない毎日も色のない夢も
Unchanging days and colorless dreams too...
手放して始めようよ
...let's let go and start anew.
不安の夜を数え
Counting anxious nights...
泣きながら迎えた朝でもいい
...even a morning welcomed in tears is fine.
時計の針のように
Like the hands of a clock...
刻んだ思い出たち広げた
...I spread out the memories carved.
戻れないから
Since I can't go back...
また愛しさが増す
...my love grows again.
キミに逢いたいよ
I want to see you.
二人で温めた大切なストーリー
The precious story we warmed together.
遠くまで続いた果てない道
The endless road that continued far away.
疲れたら代わるから そう言ってくれた
You told me, "If you get tired, I'll take your place."
優しさに触れて見えた
I touched your kindness and saw it.
受け入れてくれたこと
The fact that you accepted me...
忘れない嬉しい出来事
...a happy event I won't forget.
雨上がりの胸に
Across my heart after the rain...
架かった虹のように綺麗だ
...it's beautiful like a rainbow spanning.
キミからもらった言葉一つ一つが
Every single word I received from you...
今も宝物
...is still a treasure now.
支えてくれたから
Because you supported me...
輝けるこの気持ち届けよう
...I'll deliver this shining feeling.
時計の針のように
Like the hands of a clock...
刻んだ思い出たち広げた
...I spread out the memories carved.
戻れないから
Since I can't go back...
また愛しさが増す
...my love grows again.
キミに逢いたいよ
I want to see you.
雨上がりの胸に
Across my heart after the rain...
架かった虹のように綺麗だ
...it's beautiful like a rainbow spanning.
キミからもらった言葉一つ一つが
Every single word I received from you...
今も宝物
...is still a treasure now.
はーい、ということで、
Okaaaaay, so...
みんな、どうだったかなー？
how was it, everyone?
今回の新曲、『キミの秒針』は...
For this new song, "Kimi no Byoushin"...
シドのマオ様が作詞、
Mao-sama from SID wrote the lyrics,
そして御恵明希様が作曲、編曲...
and Aki Mimegumi-sama composed and arranged it...
そして編曲にはなんと！
And for the arrangement, believe it or not!
加藤貴之様も加わっていただきましたー！
Takayuki Kato-sama also joined in!
いや今回は、ボイスドラマ連動企画の...
Well, this time, as part of a voice drama tie-in project...
第一弾として、
as the first installment,
ストーリー全体のね、テーマソングを担うような、
it serves as the theme song for the entire story,
渾身の楽曲に仕上がっております。
and has been finished as a true masterpiece.
ま、ドラマの鍵となるね、『秒針』という...
Also, the "second hand" is key to the drama,
メタファーにも要注目してください！
so please pay close attention to that metaphor!
シドさんだけではなく、
Not only SID-san,
このあとね、豪華アーティストの皆様にも...
but afterwards, many gorgeous artists...
たくさん書いていただいたので！
wrote many songs for me, so...
皆様リリース、お楽しみにー！
everyone, please look forward to the release!
こちらの『キミの秒針』は、
As for this "Kimi no Byoushin",
各音楽サイトは...
on various music sites...
ちょっと間が空いちゃうんだけど、
there's a bit of a gap, but,
3月15日の0時から、配信予定でございまーす！
it's scheduled for distribution starting March 15th at midnight!
ま、ちょっとね、公開まで時間が空くから...
Well, since there's some time until it's public...
それまでこの配信、何度も見返してみてください！
until then, please watch this stream over and over!
聴き込んでねー！
Listen to it a lot, okay?!
そしてそして！
And, and!
MVもね、ちょっと後日公開なので...
the MV will also be released at a later date, so...
楽しみに待っててくださーい！
please wait forward to it!
ということで！
So!
今日のちょこの、生誕ライブはどうだったかなー？
how was today's Choco's birthday live?
ま、このあとは、すぐに...
Well, right after this...
ちょっとね、冒頭...
a little bit, the beginning...
最初の方でお披露目した...
that we unveiled at the start...
ノエちゃんと、ラミたんとの、3人の...
with Noe-chan and Lamy-tan, the three of us...
『初恋大戦争』の、MV公開があって...
there's the MV release for "First Love Great War"...
そのあと！
After that!
メン限で！
In the membership-only stream!
ちょっと、ライブと...
a little live, and...
撮影会の続きとか、
the continuation of the photo session,
ちょっとね、メン限でしか見れない...
and, well, things you can only see in membership...
シチュエーションドラマとかやるので！
like situation dramas!
ぜひぜひ、気になる人は見に来てくださーい！
By all means, if you're interested, please come watch!
それでは、またあとでお会いしましょう！
Alright then, let's meet again later!
おつかれいと～！はむっ！
Otsukareito~! *mwah*!